<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<opml version="1.0">
  <head>
    <title>7-30-2006</title>
    <expansionState>0,3,4,6,8,10,12,14,16,17,19,20,23,25,27</expansionState>
  </head>
  <body>
    <outline text="Opening">
      <outline text="Opening Music"/>
      <outline text="Introduction and welcome to the show."/>
    </outline>
    <outline text="News">
      <outline text="Commercial Widgets for Sale" MediaLinks="www.wdgty.com &lt;http://www.wdgty.com/&gt;">
        <outline text="The first item in the news today, is a company called widgty, is commercially making widgets available for a price of 1400 USD, to companies. They will create a widget within a week, fully branded and created to the customer’s specs. The website is wdgty.com and it looks great. You can see what widgets they have designed for other clients as well as widgets they have created for free. The service is very professional and if you are looking for a widget to be created then stop by, and check them out."/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="iCOS Comic Widget" MediaLinks="www.the8thsign.com—icos-dashboard-widget &lt;http://www.the8thsign.com/2006/07/09/icos-dashboard-widget/&gt;">
        <outline text="I stumbled upon a widget for comics, which I am not really into, but thought that this widget put a lot of features into the dashboard that other designers and programmers can appreciate. The widget is called iCos and it gets its data from an online comic database, basically the widget sports a look and feel exactly the same as iTunes only smaller. Also you can create smart lists, that will automatically sort your comic books, and preview new ones. The most amazing feature of this widget is the ability to send an email to the programmer directly from inside the widget without ever leaving dashboard. I recommend looking at it, and checking it out, it has a lot to offer, and its great to see what widget designers are doing out there."/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Magic Widgets" MediaLinks="www.macdazzle.com—ipick.html &lt;http://www.macdazzle.com/ipick.html&gt;">
        <outline text="MacDazzle, has just come out with a new widget, and if you are not familiar with MacDazzle, then basically what they create is magic trick widgets. These are dashboard widgets that perform a magic trick with support for iChat so that you can perform the trick with anyone anywhere in the world. This is also amazing and we will be featuring the iPick widget in a future show. But check it out, you can find a link again in the show notes."/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Mac World Widget" MediaLinks="Help Design the Macworld Widget Update &lt;http://phillryu.com/2006/07/21/help-design-the-macworld-widget-update/&gt;">
        <outline text="The folks over at widgetmachine.com have asked for help creating a new Mac World widget basically they are redesigning the widget and they want suggestions on things to put into the widget. Now, ultimately, the Macworld staff will have final say on what features they want and do not want, and the initial version was affected pretty heavily by their requirements. But hearing the most common complaints and requests on their blog as a comment will help them gauge what’s wanted. So head over there is a link in the show notes and help our fellow widget developers out there."/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Dashboard widgets and $$$ discussion" MediaLinks="widgetshow@gmail.com &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com&gt;">
        <outline text="This brings me to a discussion and topic that many feel is controversial and debatable, but I am going to officially open the topic for discussion here, do you think it is right for people to charge for the creation of or selling of dashboard widgets? Many people are against it, saying that widgets should be free. I feel that if the widget creator has spent a lot of time on a widget they are entitled to make the choice weather it will be a free or paid for widget. Many places charge for widgets, such as delicious monster, widget machine, equinox and of course my site Jon Brown Designs. I feel that charging for widget creation is totally acceptable, for a number of reasons, but tell me what you think send your audio comments and emails to widgetshow@gmail.com &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com&gt;"/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Dashboard Dev : Making your widget adding the on.show command" MediaLinks="dashdev.djupet.se—dashboard_widget_tutorial_4.html &lt;http://dashdev.djupet.se/dashboard_widget_tutorial_4.html&gt;">
        <outline text="if you've tried your widget, or perhaps have another widget suffering from the same problem &quot;It does not update by it self!&quot; This is the chapter for you, I will go through how to make the widget to update when you activate dashboard with the widget.onshow function.Making the widget update on it's own is necessarily if you don't want to restart it each day. You might think &quot;Well.. that's easy, just make the widget refresh every 5 minutes or so. Though, it doesn't work that way.1. These refresh scripts don't work in dashboard, have tried several html and javascripts. 2. A timer to control the update isn't optimal for this widget, because apple has provided an extra &quot;javascript&quot; function for dashboard. it's called &quot;widget.onshow&quot;, it basically tells your widget that when you activate dashboard (push F12), something is going to happen in the function you have connected to the &quot;widget.onshow&quot;.Let me show you.function UpdateWidget() { // The function: UpdateWidget // You will put the update function here }if (window.widget) { widget.onshow = UpdateWidget; // When dashboard is activated, execute the function &quot;UpdateWidget&quot; }Ok, so not we've cleared that up, how do we update the widget since these refresh scripts doesn't work? We use something called &quot;innerHTML&quot; it basically updates content in a specified location in real time, like this:function UpdateWidget { document.getElementByID(&quot;DaysLeft&quot;).innerHTML = CountDown(); }Let's go over the code pice by pice.document.getElementByID(&quot;DaysLeft&quot;) // Get the element with id &quot;DaysLeft&quot; in the document.innerHTML // Apply this function to the element (It changes the content of the element)= CountDown(); // Change the content of the element to CountDown(), that is the same as it was, in other words, it updates the function making a new value appear if a day has changed.To clarify, this script makes the widget update it's CountDown() function each time you activate dashboard.And you can find the code here:function UpdateWidget() { The function: UpdateWidget document.getElementById(&quot;DaysLeft&quot;).innerHTML = CountDown();Get the element &quot;DaysLeft&quot; in the document to change it's inner HTML to &quot;CountDown()&quot; }   if (window.widget) { widget.onshow = UpdateWidget;When the widget is shown, that is, dashboard is activated, execute the function &quot;UpdateWidget&quot; }The The Apple Javascript function is now finished, we now need to specify a section in the XHTML that will be updated each time Dashboard activates. To do this, we make a &quot;div&quot; with the id &quot;DaysLeft&quot;. Your XHTML code should look like this:&lt;html&gt; &lt;head&gt; &lt;script type='text/javascript' src='javascript.js' /&gt; &lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;  @import &quot;stylesheet.css&quot;;  &lt;/style&gt;  &lt;/head&gt; &lt;body&gt;   &lt;div id='DaysLeft'&gt; // Defines a layer (A section) and the CountDown function is placed inside the layer &lt;script type='text/javascript'&gt; document.write(CountDown()); &lt;/script&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/body&gt; &lt;/html&gt;The widget will now replace everything inside the tag with CountDown; that is, the same function, so it will work as an update.To test your function, you can change the date of your computer and activate dashboard, if the value change, you have succeeded :).And now, you have made your first widget, if you have a good countdown idea, don't be afraid to publish it, I have received many comments and mails telling me how great my StarGate Counter widget is, it's really rewarding :)."/>
      </outline>
    </outline>
    <outline text="Interview and Listener Feedback">
      <outline text="Thomas Miller the creator of The Daily Grind" MediaLinks="microcore.dk—index.php &lt;http://microcore.dk/TheDailyGrind/index.php&gt;">
        <outline text="Now time for our interview today, we are talking with the creator of “The Daily Grind” widget Thomas Miller. This widget is truly amazing; it allows you to set up different timers for different events. You can name the timer, and then change the color setting for the title, it will automatically track the amount of time for each timer, you can then edit, reset, or delete the timer, as well as copying the time to the clipboard and importing that into other programs. TheDailyGrind is a Dashboard widget that offers a lightweight approach in keeping track of time spent on tasks you perform. TheDailyGrind is designed to take up as little of your time as possible managing your time to better let you focus on getting your jobs done. It was great talking with Thomas; I hope you enjoy his great widget as well as the interview.TheDailyGrind is meant to take up as little of your time managing your time. TheDailyGrind v2 has ALT-key activated shortcuts to important functions and lets you edit hours, minutes and seconds directly. Simple, neat and painless.And of course TheDailyGrind v2 retains the features of v1: add as many trackers as you need (currently limited only by vertical screen real estate), label them accordingly and start and pause them as you see fit.Copy the contents of the tracker label and the time recorded to the clipboard for use elsewhere. And naturally TheDailyGrind retains your trackers across reboots."/>
      </outline>
    </outline>
    <outline text="Closing">
      <outline text="Submit your widget for review!">
        <outline text="Are you a widget developer or designer? Have you developed or designed something amazing? Then tell us about it! Even if you are not a designer or developer if you have made a great widget the best way is to announce it and that is where we come in."/>
        <outline text="We have a great listener base that can help you improve your widget. Let us review the widget on the show and allow people to post comments, rate and have open discussions about your creation. To submit your widget simply email the widget along with the description to widgetshow@gmail.com. &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com.&gt;"/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Contribute to the Show">
        <outline text="Review any of the products that we have reviewed here on the show, send your reviews to widgetshow@gmail.com. &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com.&gt; To get your widget added to the podcast please contact me at widgetshow@gmail.com. &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com.&gt; the shows Hotline at 206-333-0417. If you would like to contribute to the show then please send your audio comments towidgetshow@gmail.com. &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com.&gt;"/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Staff Writers Wanted">
        <outline text="If you have something to share with the widget community then drop me a line at widgetshow@gmail.com &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com&gt; and we will post your thoughts on www.widgetshow.com &lt;http://www.widgetshow.com/&gt;!" MediaLinks="widgetshow@gmail.com &lt;mailto:widgetshow@gmail.com&gt;"/>
      </outline>
      <outline text="Check out the show Forum">
        <outline text="The show forum is a place for everyone to come together and share about everything widget and dashboard related. Check it out and become a part of our user base here at the flip side." MediaLinks="forum.widgetshow.com &lt;http://forum.widgetshow.com/&gt;"/>
      </outline>
    </outline>
  </body>
</opml>
